	var db = [{ //this is 0
    "question": " Welcome to <em>Submerged</em> ! Who do you want to play as?",
    "question1": " ",
    "question2": " ",
    "question3": " ",
    "question4": " ",
    "question5": " ",
    "answers": [{ 
        "title": "Adam, the human (he/him/his)",
        "response": 1
      },
      {
        "title": "Vari, the explorer (she/her/hers)",
        "response": 100
      },
      {
        "title": "Ula, the jeweler (ey/em/eirs)",
        "response": 50
      }
    ]
  },
  { //this is 1
    "question": "TW: This route involves descriptions and discussions of drowning. Do you want to continue?",
    "question1": "",
    "question2": "",
    "question3": "",
    "question4": "",
    "question5": "",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "Yes, let's begin!",
      "response": 2
    },
    {
    	"title": "No, take me back to the start",
    	"response": 0
    }
    ]
  },
  { //this is 2
    "question": "It’s dark, and cold, and you can’t see- you can’t breathe. But you haven’t found it yet, you haven’t....",
    "question1": " ",
    "question2": " ",
    "question3": "",
    "question4": "",
    "question5": "",
    "answers": [{
        "title": "Where is it?",
        "response": 3
      },
    ]
  },
  { //this is 3
    "question": "It’s really so, very dark.",
    "question1": "You can feel the pressure on your lungs start to mount, to become unbearable, and with a heavy heart turn to what you assume is the way up.",
    "question2": "It's becoming harder to think, and you can feel yourself becoming weaker",
    "question3": "You move your limbs desperately, but the pressure is only getting tighter, it’s only getting darker, it’s only getting harder to move. You start flailing desperately.",
    "question4": "You can’t die yet, you have to get back home!",
    "question5": " ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "Steve....",
      "response": 4
    }
    ]
  },

 { //this is 4
    "question": "Suddenly, something heavy is crashing into you, and you involuntarily open your mouth.",
    "question1": "The water rushes in and you start to choke, but leathery flippers are grabbing at your face, pulling you closer.",
    "question2": "You thrash around, trying your best to survive, still, but the creature is stronger than you. You feel leatherly lips crash against your face, pointy teeth cut into your cheek, and then.....",
    "question3": "You're breathing? You’re breathing! The pressure, the burning in your lungs, the darkness, they all subside.",
    "question4": "In front of your spotty vision is a leathery face, creased with worry.",
    "question5": "What the fuck?  That’s... a seal...",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "But it's also a person?",
      "response": 5
    }]
  },

{ //this is 5
    "question": "“Oh thank god!” The seal-person says, manhandling you, checking you for injuries.",
    "question1": "They wince once they see the small cuts their teeth made into your cheek, then release you, chucking softly.",
    "question2": "“I know this is very disorienting,” The seal-person says in response, putting a slight bit of distance between the two of you.",
    "question3": "“And I’m sorry for kissing you. It was the only way to save you from drowning. It’s like.... What’s that thing you humans have? CPT?” ",
    "question4": "You find your voice “It’s.... CPR....”",
    "question5": "The seal-person claps their flippers together in recognition. “Yeah, that! Glad you’re not dead!” Their smile is sharp, toothy.",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "Introduce yourself",
      "response": 6
    },
    {
      "title": "Stare",
      "response": 7
    }]
  },

{ //this is 6
    "question": "“Well.... thanks for saving my life.” It comes out more like a question, your heart pounding incessantly. “I’m Adam. He/him.....”",
    "question1": "Does this creature even have a concept of pronouns? Why even introduce yourself in the first place?",
    "question2": "“I’m Ronen! He/him/his also!!” Ronen swims closer to you in his excitement, and it takes everything in you not to scramble back.",
    "question3": "",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "What now?",
      "response": 13
    }]
  },

{ //this is 7
    "question": "You’re vaguely aware of your hands and legs treading the water, but you’re still in some form of shock. The teeth don’t help.",
    "question1": "“I’m Ronen! He/him/his! What’s your name?” ",
    "question2": "“....Adam. He/him/his also....”",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "There’s more silence.",
      "response": 13
    }]
  },

{ //this is 13
    "question": "“So! Do you need help getting back home or something?” ",
    "question1": "The question shocks you into remembrance.  ",
    "question2": " “Ack! The ring!”",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "You have to find it! ",
      "response": 14
    }]
  },

{ //this is 14
    "question": "You thrash around in the water, hoping against hope that you’ll catch a glimpse of gold somewhere in the dark murk.",
    "question1": "You’re about to dive further down in a random direction when Ronen stops you.",
    "question2": "“What are you doing??”  ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "Explain.",
      "response": 15
    }
    ]
  },

{ //this is 15
    "question": "“The- the ring. I’ve been carrying this engagement ring with me everywhere, and it fell out, and- it was perfect for him, I really need to find it!”  ",
    "question1": "Ronen nods and mirrors you, diving down into the murky depths. The force with which he propels himself forward surprises you, but you don’t dwell on it long, focusing on the task at hand.  ",
    "question2": "Look: ",
    "answers": [
    {
      "title": "Left ",
      "response": 16
    },
    {
      "title": "Right ",
      "response": 18
    }
    ]
  },

{ //this is 16
    "question": "Nothing. ",
    "question1": " ",
    "question2": "Look: ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "Right ",
      "response": 17
    }]
  },

{ //this is 17
    "question": "Nothing. ",
    "question1": " ",
    "question2": " ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "Still nothing. ",
      "response": 20
    }]
  },

{ //this is 18
    "question": "Nothing. ",
    "question1": " ",
    "question2": "Look: ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "Left ",
      "response": 19
    }
    ]
  },

{ //this is 19
    "question": "Nothing. ",
    "question1": " ",
    "question2": " ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "Still nothing. ",
      "response": 20
    }]
  },

{ //this is 20
    "question": "You’re starting to despair. The ring really was perfect, and expensive. But it was ___’s favorite gemstone, and beautifully fashioned. It wasn’t often you could afford to splurge on your boyfriend- not with a fisherman’s salary- and, well, a marriage proposal seemed worth it. ",
    "question1": "It <em> is </em> worth it. You really need to find this ring.  ",
    "question2": "You renew your search with vigor, and after a while, Ronen swims up to you. ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "“Found it?” ",
      "response": 21
    }]
  },

{ //this is 21
    "question": "He shakes his head ruefully, and your heart sinks. Just as he opens his mouth to speak, you hear voices calling out his name.  ",
    "question1": "He’s quick to grab your arm- is it alarm? Excitement?- and swims upward rapidly, almost ramming into them.  ",
    "question2": "The figures are fairly menacing- if you thought Ronen was someone to be wary of, these were creatures to be feared. Between the sharp teeth, claws, armor, spear, and the gnarly missing arm, you weren’t sure where to stand. Er, swim. ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "Protect Ronen ",
      "response": 22
    },
    {
      "title": "Hide behind Ronen ",
      "response": 24
    }
    ]
  },

{ //this is 22
    "question": "You’re not sure if they mean Ronen harm, but they won’t get to do anything about that as long as you’re around. ___ has always told you- with a mix of fondness and exasperation- that you’re too heroic for your good. You’re not sure if you’d call it heroism, but Ronen’s sweet, and he saved you. You’re not about to let him get speared. ",
    "question1": "You move your body in front of his and stare the figures down. You hope you don’t look as scared as you feel. ",
    "question2": "“Who are you?”  ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "Real intimidating, Adam. ",
      "response": 23
    }]
  },

{ //this is 23
    "question": "The shark looms over you, teeth flashing dangerous and eyes narrowing. ",
    "question1": "“Who are <em> you </em>?” ",
    "question2": "Out of the corner of your eyes, you can see the other one readying their spear. Before y’all can continue antagonizing each other, Ronen peeks out from behind you with a wide smile. ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "I’m guessing we’re not in danger? ",
      "response": 25
    }]
  },

{ //this is 24
    "question": "Uh, yeah, Ronen is more than capable of protecting himself. You can barely see, can barely <em> swim </em> compared to all these sea creatures. You’ll sit this one out, thanks. ",
    "question1": "From beside you, Ronen smiles wide. ",
    "question2": " ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "Doesn’t seem like you were needed, after all.",
      "response": 25
    }]
  },

{ //this is 25
    "question": "“Sasa! Tsurva! This is Adam.” Ronen’s moved to stand between you and the group, and gestures gently. Tsurva, the shark, appraises you while Sasa lays webbed fingers on Ronen’s shoulder. ",
    "question1": "“We were worried, you took a while.” ",
    "question2": "“WE?” Tsurva says with an antagonizing grin. “Ze wouldn’t stop moaning about ‘oh, what if he got hurt, oh what if this, what if that’ waah waah waah.” ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "Ok, so they’re friends. ",
      "response": 26
    }]
  },

{ //this is 26
    "question": "Ze flushes slightly, but rolls hir eyes. “She’s acting as though she wasn’t equally worried.” This elicits a snort from Ronen, and an undignified noise from Tsurva.",
    "question1": "“You wouldn’t have come if that was the case.” Sasa insists. ",
    "question2": "“Well, as you can see, I’m fine! I just saw Adam in trouble and had to help him, that’s all.”  ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "Nod ",
      "response": 27
    }]
  },

{ //this is 27
    "question": "Sasa fixes you with hir gaze, equally unsettling and _like something to show ze’s a protector__. ",
    "question1": "“Are you unwell?” Ze asks. ",
    "question2": "“I’m fine now, thanks. I just need to find my ring and then I’ll be good to go home.” ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "Speaking of... ",
      "response": 28
    }]
  },

{ //this is 28
    "question": "Ronen winces and sends you a pitiful look. ",
    "question1": "“I’m sorry Adam, I think it’s gone.....” ",
    "question2": "“Oh....” The stress of the past hour seems to catch up to you all in a rush. ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "Here come the tears!!! ",
      "response": 29
    }]
  },

{ //this is 29
    "question": "You turn away from the group, who mercifully give you space. Crying underwater is... strange. The tears mix with the seawater immediately, but your chest heaves and you can’t stop the weird, choked noises that leave you. You can hear Ronen explaining quietly behind you. ",
    "question1": "You wonder briefly what this experience would be like if you couldn’t magically breathe underwater- would you drown? From crying? You should thank Ronen again.",
    "question2": "It takes you a minute to collect yourself, between the overwhelming stress and the idle wonderings about death. You steady your breath and run your hand over your face before turning back to the group with a wry smile.  ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "This sucks... ",
      "response": 30
    }]
  },

{ //this is 30
    "question": "“Well.... Thanks for saving me Ronen. Better my life than the ring, huh?” You chuckle dryly. ",
    "question1": "Tsurva shoots Sasa a glance and sucks her teeth. ",
    "question2": "“Ok, am I the only one that’s gonna bring up the cave?”  ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "What cave? ",
      "response": 31
    }]
  },

{ //this is 31
    "question": "Sasa goes rigid, glaring at her. “That’s dangerous.” Ze hisses. ",
    "question1": "“So? He’s clearly willing to risk it. He almost drowned for the ring, after all!” ",
    "question2": "“He <em> just </em> said it was better to come out with his life than with a ring!” ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "“Someone fill me in.” ",
      "response": 32
    }]
  },

{ //this is 32
    "question": "Ronen glances at Sasa briefly. “There’s this infamous cave...” ",
    "question1": "“Ronen.” Sasa hisses. ",
    "question2": "“Look, Sasa, he should at least get to know now that we brought it up.” ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": " “Yeah, tell me.” ",
      "response": 33
    }]
  },


{ //this is 33
    "question": "Sasa groans and crosses hir arms, but otherwise remains quiet as hir companions explain. ",
    "question1": "“We know of a cave that has a bunch of gems and shit, priceless things, but it’s chock full of traps. Taken as many lives as it’s made rich.” Tsurva absentmindedly scratches at her missing arm as she speaks. Sasa’s face creases in worry, but ze remains tight-lipped. ",
    "question2": "Ronen nods. “There’s a few legends surrounding it, and <em> why </em> there’s so much loot, who sets up the traps in the first place, etc. But Sasa’s right- it’s pretty dangerous.” ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "Interesting... ",
      "response": 34
    }]
  },


{ //this is 34
    "question": "“It wouldn’t be <em> easy </em>, but if we can get to the room with the loot, you could pick out the materials for a baller ring. Better than the one you lost, I bet.” ",
    "question1": "“Yeah, we have a jeweler friend who we could ask for help. He won’t do it if you don’t provide materials, though, so we’d have to go through the cave.” Ronen pauses to look at Sasa. ",
    "question2": "“Should we put it up to a vote?” He asks. ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "No ",
      "response": 35
    },
    {
      "title": "Yes ",
      "response": 47
    }]
  },

{ //this is 35
    "question": "You shake your head. “I’m just a fisherman, and I’ve tempted death once already. I better just get back home to my boyfriend and find another way to get him a ring....” ",
    "question1": "Tsurva looks a bit disappointed, but everyone seems to respect your decision, Sasa most of all. ",
    "question2": "“Let’s get you back home.” Ronen says with a smile. You nod, shooting him a small smile in return. ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "Swim up ",
      "response": 36
    }]
  },


{ //this is 36
    "question": "All four of you swim up, and in the vague direction of where you think your boat is. You were hoping you’d be better able to locate it once you broke through the surface, but it’s pitch dark, and you have to rely on your companion’s senses to locate it. ",
    "question1": "Once you do, they help you get back on board- with a few snide comments from Tsurva about your clumsiness.  ",
    "question2": " ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "Time for the goodbyes ",
      "response": 37
    }]
  },

{ //this is 37
    "question": "“Well... Thanks.” ",
    "question1": "“Losing your ring was unfortunate, but I believe your partner will value your safe return above all.” ",
    "question2": "You smile at Sasa in appreciation, and state your goodbyes, watching as all three of them return underwater. ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "Time to head home ",
      "response": 38
    }]
  },


{ //this is 38
    "question": "You take a moment to sit in the dark, shivering, before you turn on the lights. The journey back is longer and colder than you’d like. You’re eager to get under the blankets with your boyfriend and snuggle. ",
    "question1": "You drag your heavy bones into your shared home, trying to make as little noise as possible. If he’s already sleeping, you don’t want to wake him.... Although you’d really love his company after the strange day you’ve had. ",
    "question2": "You’re peeling off the damp layers when the light turns on. ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "Ah, he's up. ",
      "response": 39
    }]
  },

{ //this is 39
    "question": "Your boyfriend stands in the doorway to your room, sleepy and adorable in one of your old t-shirts and sleep shorts. ",
    "question1": "“You’re back.” His voice is raspy. You woke him, damn you. ",
    "question2": "You move towards him with an apologetic grin, a warm, fuzzy feeling creeping up your chest. You couldn’t stop it even if you wanted to. ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "Apologize for waking him.... and the time. ",
      "response": 40
    }]
  },

{ //this is 40
    "question": "“Sorry, sweetheart. Go back to bed, I’ll join you after I shower.” ",
    "question1": "He leans up to give you a soft peck, which turns into a hiss as he intertwines your fingers. ",
    "question2": "“Why are your hands so cold.” It’s accusatory, and pouty, but he takes them between his own and blows on them, bringing warmth to the tips. ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "Look on fondly. You love him so much. ",
      "response": 41
    }]
  },

{ //this is 41
    "question": "“I’ll explain tomorrow, I promise. Right now I just want to shower and go to bed. Cuddle.” ",
    "question1": "Steve hums in approval, giving you another peck before you briefly part ways.  ",
    "question2": " ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "Warm water only, please. ",
      "response": 42
    }]
  },

{ //this is 42
    "question": "You wash the sea brine off of you, finally processing the day’s events. You let yourself cry again, cathartic, and will the water to wash away all the bad things. A near-death experience like that is nothing to joke about. ",
    "question1": "But you’re alive, and you’re home. There’s much to be grateful for. ",
    "question2": " ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "Time for cuddles with your boyfriend. You deserve it. ",
      "response": 43
    }]
  },

{ //this is 43
    "question": "You pad back into your shared bedroom, worming your way into the sheets and the arms of your lover. It’s not until this moment that you realize you finally feel safe again. ",
    "question1": "“Baby” You murmur. ",
    "question2": "“Hmmm.” ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "Propose ",
      "response": 44
    },
    {
      "title": "Tell him you love him",
      "response": 46
    }
    ]
  },

{ //this is 44
    "question": " You reach blindly for his face, cupping his cheek. You're not usually a man of many words- and you're kind of overwhelmed with emotion right now, to be honest- so you go for simple.",
    "question1": "“Marry me. I want to spend the rest of my life with you.” ",
    "question2": "You hear his sharp gasp, and the rustle of sheets. ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "Wait for an answer. ",
      "response": 45
    }]
  },

{ //this is 45
    "question": "“Yes!” And then he’s kissing you, and you’re home. ",
    "question1": "You're loved. ",
    "question2": " ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "The End! ",
      "response": 100000
    },
    {
      "title": "Start Over. ",
      "response": 0
    }]
  },

{ //this is 46
    "question": "“I love you.” ",
    "question1": "“I love you too, baby.” ",
    "question2": " ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "The End! ",
      "response": 10000
    },
    {
      "title": "Start Over. ",
      "response": 0
    }
    ]
  },

{ //this is 47
    "question": "You nod. ",
    "question1": "“If you guys are alright with it, I am. I’d do anything for Steve.” ",
    "question2": "“Ok then. On the count of three, raise your hand for yes. One... Two... Three...” ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "Vote ",
      "response": 49
    }]
  },

{ //this is 48
    "question": "Both you and Tsurva raise your hands confidently, and immediately. Ronen hesitates for a second but does the same, to Sasa’s chagrin. Ze curses in a tongue you don’t recognize. ",
    "question1": "“I’m sorry, Sasa. It’s for love.” Ronen speaks gently, flippers settling on hir forearms. Sasa’s jaw is set in anger, but ze closes hir eyes and attempts to relax. After a second, ze opens them again and whispers something to Ronen. ",
    "question2": "You turn away slightly to give them privacy, eyes meeting with Tsurva. She fake gags in your direction, and you stifle a soft laugh. ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "Strengthen your resolve.",
      "response": 49
    }]
  },

{ //this is 49
    "question": "“Alright.” Sasa says, squaring hir shoulders.",
    "question1": "“Let’s go.”  ",
    "question2": " ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "Adventure! ",
      "response": 101
    }]
  },

{ //this is 50
    "question": "You’re not one to brag, but you’re one of the best at what you do. Explorers come from all over the seas with jewels, gems, and trinkets, asking for you to create your art. It’s a rewarding way to pass the time, and it’s pretty flattering! But maybe your favorite part of it all is the trade aspect. ",
    "question1": "Regular callers mostly just bring you fish, shells, and the like- everyday necessities- but those that travel far usually offer more, and the mystery in that thrills you. ",
    "question2": "Sometimes they trade some of their own jewelry, or art pieces. Sometimes it’s songs, poems, stories, knowledge. Occasionally they’ll even bring you trinkets from the human world. ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "One time, someone brought a legend. ",
      "response": 51
    }]
  },

{ //this is 51
    "question": "It was one of those rare days where the ocean felt like it had stilled. Tsurva, a close friend, was helping you set up the new space. ",
    "question1": "You used to take calls at your house, when you first started years ago, but weren’t a fan of having so many complete strangers in your living space. With Tsurva’s help, you’d fashioned out an additional space near your home in order to receive traders. ",
    "question2": "One of these traders wondered in, with the prettiest conch you’d ever seen. ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "Your hands itched with anticipation. ",
      "response": 52
    }]
  },

{ //this is 52
    "question": "Tsurva had openly laughed at you, jokingly warning your visitor to keep an eye on the conch if ne didn’t want it stolen. In response, you had very maturely stuck out your tongue and flicked her on the arm. ",
    "question1": "Together, you and the stranger talked through nir expectations for the piece. You delighted in making Tsurva swim around fixing up the space while you chatted, sending each other dirty glares when the trader wasn’t looking. ",
    "question2": " ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "Ne never noticed. ",
      "response": 53
    }]
  },

{ //this is 53
    "question": "You like to talk to the traders as you work. You like getting to know the people who are taking home your creations, and doing so often influences how the piece comes out in the end. ",
    "question1": "This one in particular really loved legends, grand tales about your world and what shaped it. Ne offered up several stories for trade, and you listened eagerly. ",
    "question2": "There were several stories of creation, but even more of special landmarks and the heroes of your waters. ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "It was the heroes that captured Tsurva’s attention. ",
      "response": 54
    }]
  },

{ //this is 54
    "question": "She demanded more stories of Dzli, the mighty. An (in)famous explorer of several generations past, Tsurva ate up every legend, every word uttered about her, roaring in laughter and listening raptly. ",
    "question1": " ",
    "question2": " ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "As you finished up, your entertainer had one more story for you. ",
      "response": 55
    }]
  },

{ //this is 55
    "question": "“Have you two heard of Sagandzuri?” Ne had asked. There was a shift in nir tone that you hadn’t missed. ",
    "question1": "You and Tsurva looked at each other, leaning in closer to the trader. ",
    "question2": "“Tell us.” ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "Ne settled in nir seat, savoring your attention. ",
      "response": 56
    }]
  },

{ //this is 56
    "question": "“There are several legends about it, but it’s getting late, so I’ll tell you only two.” Ne began. “The one thing everyone can agree on is the existence of Sagandzuri, and the wonders inside. I think you in particular would love it, Ula; it’s filled with all the beauties of the sea, gold and gems and trinkets that would make the conch pale in comparison. You’d be able to make masterpieces with the treasures that cave contains.”  ",
    "question1": "Your fingers twitched by your side, but you didn’t dare interrupt. ",
    "question2": "“They say it’s located between Stargazer Valley and Eshavul Volcano, past the binicles. Some say these are metaphors, that as vast as the sea is, if all these existed together, we’d know about it. Others say it’s arrogant to underestimate the sea.” ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "Ne flashes you a grin. ",
      "response": 57
    }]
  },

{ //this is 57
    "question": "“Who discovered the cave, kept up the traps? Who gave it its’ name? How did the riches of the ocean end up in one place? No one knows. One legend involves the Meomrebi.” ",
    "question1": "The Meomrebi were part of one of the previous stories, a school of merfish made up of vicious warriors. Back when the humans traversed the seas in their wooden ships- no match for the careful planning and years of practiced skill of merfish- the Meomrebi would sink them by the dozen, hunting the humans as they were hunted. That practice has since died out, but the Meomrebi live on in legends such as these. ",
    "question2": "“Supposedly, when they would sink a ship with lots of human goods in them- riches from wars and conflicts we know little of- they would gather up their spoils and transport them to Sagandzuri. Imagine it- the goods of thousands of ships, accumulating over the years. They say that once word got around about the existence of Sagandzuri, other merfish started to come around in hopes of getting lucky while the Meomrebi were out pillaging.” ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "It was succsessful enough, in the beginning.",
      "response": 58
    }]
  },

{ //this is 58
    "question": "“The Meomrebi worked better as a group; you need numbers for what they were doing. It just wasn’t practical to expand a number of their forces in protecting the cave. So they started up setting intricate traps, increasing in difficulty the closer you got to the cavern in which the spoils were kept. It’s said that when a Meomrebi died, they returned to Sagandzuri in order to protect the ttreasures. Ghosts, their soul, their essence, whatever you want to call it- they journeyed back to continue in death as in life. That’s why, if it’s ever found, the traps will still protect the cave from anyone unworthy.” ",
    "question1": "Ne paused nir tale, taking a careful sip of jellyfish tea and gauging your reactions. ",
    "question2": "Tsurva snarled, unimpressed. ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "You tuted at the display of aggression. ",
      "response": 59
    }]
  },

{ //this is 59
    "question": "“That’s complete bullshit. Firstly, we have enough treasures in the ocean, thank you very much. No way Sagandzuri is filled only with human garbage. And there’s also no way ghosts are real.” ",
    "question1": "Ne had shrugged cordially. “Like I said, call it whatever you want, but that’s how the legend goes.” ",
    "question2": "“Well it’s a shoddy one.” Tsurva grumbled, ignoring your indignant exclamation. ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "Thankfully, the traveller hadn’t seemed insulted. ",
      "response": 60
    }]
  },

{ //this is 60
    "question": "“Well, you’ll like this last one, Tsurva.” Ne said with a laugh. “It involves Dzli”. ",
    "question1": "Tsurva grinned immediately, sharp teeth glinting in the light. ",
    "question2": " ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": " “Lay it on me!” She had cheered.",
      "response": 61
    }]
  },

{ //this is 61
    "question": "Ne was more than happy to indulge the audience. ",
    "question1": "“As you know, Dzli was part of a generation of exceptional explorers. A prideful, competitive bunch. Well, Matsi, one of Dzli’s rivals, found Sagandzuri in one of xyr many escapades. At the time, it was simply a cave, but Matsi liked the challenges it presented, simply based on location. Xe had some friends independently set up the cave with traps, and challenged xyr fellow explorers to one of many frequent competitions. The goal was to obtain an object- the most valuable thing they’d found- and get it safely into the depths of the cave, be the first to do so. Participants would be judged on a number of other things as well, including value of object, mastery over the traps, and size of the object. It was a popular challenge; they indulged in it often, so much so that the cave was soon filled with wonders. Eventually, it became the famous Sagandzuri of legend. Dzli was supposedly a frequent player, and winner.” ",
    "question2": "“Dzli the mighty!” Tsurva roared in approval. ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "You all laughed. ",
      "response": 62
    }]
  },

{ //this is 62
    "question": "Having finished nir stories, and you having fashioned the shell to nir liking, the trader bid you goodbye. ",
    "question1": "In nir absence, you were suddenly aware of the quiet of the ocean. ",
    "question2": "Tsurva hadn’t seemed to notice, swept up in the grandeur of the legends. ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": " As you parted ways, you couldn’t help but feel something had changed. ",
      "response": 63
    }]
  },

{ //this is 63
    "question": "In the days after the trader’s visit, mentions of Sagandzuri started popping up everywhere. Like when you learn something new, and suddenly you could see traces of it everywhere. ",
    "question1": "Just as ne had said, the legends of how the cave came to be were abundant, and varied. But everyone could agree that there were wonders in that cave, the likes of which had your fingers twitching. ",
    "question2": "You try not to pay too much attention to the rumors, leaving them as just that. ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "Tsurva seeks them out. ",
      "response": 64
    }]
  },

{ //this is 64
    "question": "She talks of Dzli fairly often, but that’s normal. ",
    "question1": "Then she starts exploring-- small things, first bringing you gifts of shells, unusual fish, shiny trinkets. As her skills increase, so does the value in your gifts. ",
    "question2": "You don’t start to worry until she leaves for longer periods of time, returning with new cuts and injuries. You scold her gently, patch her up, but she just laughs and proudly presents you with more materials. ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": " You have to patch her up more often than you’d like. ",
      "response": 65
    }]
  },

{ //this is 65
    "question": "Talks of Dzli morph into talks of Sagandzuri. Often, these follow several lines of discussion; the prestige in finding and traversing the cave. The treasures you could have at your disposal. The excitement of finding a thing of legend, of sharing it with the world. ",
    "question1": "You can’t lie- it had thrilled you in equal measures. But out of the two of you, you’d always been the more cautious one, and you urged Tsurva to be careful in her journeys. You worried that, in her excitement, she would become careless one day. ",
    "question2": "She already had the wounds to match. ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "She always promised you she’d take care of herself, roaring with laughter.  ",
      "response": 66
    }]
  },

{ //this is 66
    "question": "The next time you saw her, Tsurva had lost an arm. ",
    "question1": " ",
    "question2": " ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "Her <em> arm</em>. ",
      "response": 67
    }]
  },

{ //this is 67
    "question": "She had found Sagandzuri, or at least what she thought was the cave. Her arm had caught in one of the traps, and-- well. All that was left now was part of her forearm. ",
    "question1": "You hadn’t know what to say. You had sat inside your house with her, held her shaking body, and the sea felt still once more. ",
    "question2": "She promised not to return to Sagandzuri. ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "Talk of the cave stopped. ",
      "response": 68
    }]
  },

{ //this is 68
    "question": "That had been before. It took her a while to get used to the missing arm, but Tsurva’s always been determined. She still explores the seas, bringing you gifts once she’s home. You’re fairly sure she doesn’t care for the treasures themselves, but rather the adrenaline that exploring brings. ",
    "question1": "She finds companions- a warrior and a healer. In no time at all, Sasa and Ronen become dear friends, protective as you are of them. ",
    "question2": "You’re happy. ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "You're safe. ",
      "response": 69
    }]
  },

{ //this is 69
    "question": "You fall into a comfortable routine. ",
    "question1": "Tsurva and Sasa go out to explore, with Ronen in tow. You spend the days of their absence with traders, basking in their company and their offerings while working with the materials your friends bring you. When they come back- with more spoils- you fuss over them, making them food, listening to their accounts of what happened. They’ll take a break from exploring, either to look for new leads or just to spend time at home.  ",
    "question2": "As much as you love the gifts, this is your favorite part. ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "You miss them when they’re gone. You worry. ",
      "response": 70
    }]
  },

{ //this is 70
    "question": "This time around, they’ve been gone for longer than you’d expected them to, had left in a hush. You’ve had some visitors (traders), but you’re bored.  ",
    "question1": "The sea is still. ",
    "question2": " ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "You hear them before you see them, unusually boisterous. ",
      "response": 71
    }]
  },

{ //this is 71
    "question": "“Do you think ey missed us?” Ronen’s voice reaches you first, gentle as always. ",
    "question1": "“Of course ey did! Missed me, at least. Don’t know about you lot!” Tsurva says with her roaring laugh. ",
    "question2": "“Don’t be obnoxious, Tsurva.” Sasa chides, and you finally see their forms in the distance.",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "You call out to them in excitement. ",
      "response": 72
    }]
  },

{ //this is 72
    "question": "“ULA!” Tsurva roars, hoisting her arm up in greeting. The bag in her fist swings around wildly, but Ronen ducks swiftly out of the way. He turns to smile and wave at you, and Sasa nods, offering up a rare grin. ",
    "question1": "You swim out to them eagerly, tackling all three in a big hug. ",
    "question2": "“You assholes sure left quietly this time around.” ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "It’s Ronen’s tense laugh that tips you off. Something’s wrong. ",
      "response": 73
    }]
  },

{ //this is 73
    "question": "You part from them slowly, eyes narrowed in suspicion, and finally register the sheer amount of treasures they’re carrying. ",
    "question1": "“That’s a lot of loot.” ",
    "question2": "Sasa’s eyes meet Ronen’s, but neither say anything. Tsurva grins at you, but it’s slightly strained. ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "“Yep! Let’s get it inside first. I’m starving.” ",
      "response": 74
    }]
  },

{ //this is 74
    "question": "She moves past you and into your house, the others hesitating slightly but following suit. ",
    "question1": "You’re conscious of the sea’s silence now,  like eyes on the back of your neck. ",
    "question2": "Anger and fear mount in you, but you try to shove them down. ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "You close the door softly, facing away from them. ",
      "response": 75
    }]
  },

{ //this is 75
    "question": "“Tsurva.” Your voice is quiet, even. “Where did you go?” ",
    "question1": "There’s a beat of silence, and your fingers itch. ",
    "question2": "You hear her sigh deeply before she speaks.  ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "“Sagandzuri.” ",
      "response": 76
    }]
  },

{ //this is 76
    "question": "There’s something in the way you whirl around that makes Ronen flinch, makes Sasa’s hand reflexively move towards hir weapon.  ",
    "question1": "“You <em> promised </em> me you’d never go back!”  ",
    "question2": "“Hear me out” She says, hand raised in warning. ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "Calm yourself down",
      "response": 77
    }]
  },

{ //this is 77
    "question": "You still yourself and close your eyes, tensing your entire body before relaxing. It’s a tactic you use when your anger gets ahead of you- a way for your body to release your intense emotions. Your friends wait patiently until you open your eyes once more. ",
    "question1": "“Alright. I’m listening. I hope you have a good explanation.”",
    "question2": "“Thank you.” Tsurva says, swimming up to you and hesitantly taking your hand. ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "Let her (platonic). ",
      "response": 78
    },
    {
      "title": "Let her (romantic). ",
      "response": 85
    }
    ]
  },

{ //this is 78
    "question": "You let her, squeezing her hand in reassurance. You’re still angry, but that anger comes from your love for her. ",
    "question1": "“I’m sorry I broke our promise. And that I... deceived you. It’s just that I.. I <em>had</em> to, Ula.” ",
    "question2": "“<em> Why? </em>” ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "You can’t understand it. ",
      "response": 79
    }]
  },

{ //this is 79
    "question": "She looks down at your hands, gathering up her words. It’s strange seeing her this hesitant, so you make an effort to relax. To put her at ease. ",
    "question1": "“I don’t know how to explain it, exactly. Ever since that night...” You flinch at the memory of her despair. “... it feels like I’ve been swimming away from Sagandzuri, like I’ve been letting my fear lead me blindly. Got tired of it. Just... felt like it was time to face it.” ",
    "question2": " ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "“Why didn’t you <em> tell </em> me?” ",
      "response": 80
    }]
  },

{ //this is 80
    "question": "You’re hurt by all the secrecy. Hurt that Sasa and Ronen went along with it. ",
    "question1": "Ronen swims up to you and Tsurva, placing a flipper on her shoulder. Then, gently; ",
    "question2": "“Ula, you’re completely unapproachable when it comes to Sagandzuri. Tsurva <em> tried </em> bringing it up a couple of times, but lost her nerve.” ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "Tsurva looks to the side at this, put off by the admission.  ",
      "response": 81
    }]
  },

{ //this is 81
    "question": "“You're my best friend. Your opinions matter to me. But I had to do this. Didn’t wanna turn tail.” ",
    "question1": "It takes you a minute to process this, to come to terms with it. ",
    "question2": "“I don’t really get it, but... I should have supported you, if that’s what you want.” ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "Everyone’s relief is palpable.",
      "response": 82
    }]
  },

{ //this is 82
    "question": "“But!”",
    "question1": "They tense up at the sudden sharpness of your tone. ",
    "question2": "“Never lie to me again. Never deceive me like this. I’ll make an effort to be less...aggressive about things that scare me, but you can’t hide things like this from me. You’re my friends, and I love you all. I care for you all deeply.” ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "Sasa cracks one of hir rare smiles. ",
      "response": 83
    }]
  },

{ //this is 83
    "question": "“We promise.” ",
    "question1": "You look pointedly at Tsurva, who chuckles and smiles sheepishly at you. ",
    "question2": "“Promise. Won’t break this one, either.” ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": " “You better not.” You warn. ",
      "response": 84
    }]
  },

{ //this is 84
    "question": "She can’t help it- she brings you into a suffocating hug. Ronen laughs, and joins in, pulling Sasa along. It’s so familiar, so welcome. You hug them back just as tightly. After a minute, Tsurva speaks up. ",
    "question1": " “Ula?” ",
    "question2": "  “Hmm?” ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "“Don’t kill me for this... but what do you think of going through Sagandzuri?” ",
      "response": 101
    }]
  },

{ //this is 85
    "question": "You let her, feel your anger dwindle- after all, she’s here. She’s safe. ",
    "question1": "Your eyes flicker briefly to her missing arm, and you can’t stop yourself from tightening your hold on her. ",
    "question2": "“I’m sorry I broke our promise. And that I... deceived you. It’s just that I.. I <em>had</em> to, Ula.” ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": " “<em> Why? </em>” ",
      "response": 86
    }]
  },

{ //this is 86
    "question": "She looks down and delicately runs her clawed finger over your palm. It makes you shiver. ",
    "question1": "“I don’t know how to explain it, exactly. Ever since that night...” You flinch at the memory of her despair. “... it feels like I’ve been swimming away from Sagandzuri, like I’ve been letting my fear lead me blindly. Got tired of it. Just... felt like it was time to face it.” ",
    "question2": "You can’t help it. The words leave your mouth, lay your intentions bare. ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "“Without me.” ",
      "response": 87
    }]
  },

{ //this is 87
    "question": "You can’t hold Tsurva’s stare, earnest as it is. Her being this openly vulnerable, holding you, speaking to you softly- it disarms you. ",
    "question1": "“You’ve never explored before, Ula. I... If you had gotten...” She swallows thick. “I wasn’t gonna chance it.” ",
    "question2": "“Just your life.” You glance behind her. “The lives of our friends.” ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": " Sasa’s ears flap indignantly. ",
      "response": 88
    }]
  },

{ //this is 88
    "question": "“We came on our own accord.” ",
    "question1": "Ronen swims up to you and Tsurva, placing a flipper on her shoulder. Then, gently; ",
    "question2": "“Ula, you’re completely unapproachable when it comes to Sagandzuri. Tsurva <em> tried </em> bringing it up a couple of times, but lost her nerve.” ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "Tsurva looks to the side at this, put off by the admission.  ",
      "response": 89
    }]
  },

{ //this is 89
    "question": "“You.... your... opinions matter to me. But I had to do this. Didn’t wanna turn tail.” ",
    "question1": " You stay quiet for a minute. ",
    "question2": "“Okay.” The release of tension is palpable. ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "“But!” ",
      "response": 90
    }]
  },

{ //this is 90
    "question": "Tsurva tenses up at the sudden sharpness of your tone. ",
    "question1": "“Never lie to me again. Never deceive me like this. I’ll make an effort to be less...aggressive about things that scare me, but you can’t hide things like this from me. You’re my friends, and I love you all. I care for you all deeply.” ",
    "question2": "Sasa cracks one of hir rare smiles. ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": " “We promise.” ",
      "response": 91
    }]
  },

{ //this is 91
    "question": "You look pointedly at Tsurva, who smiles sheepishly at you. ",
    "question1": "“Promise. Won’t break this one, either.” ",
    "question2": "“You better not.” You warn.  ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "She can’t help it- she brings you into a suffocating hug. ",
      "response": 92
    }]
  },

{ //this is 92
    "question": "It’s so familiar, so welcome. You hug her back just as tightly. ",
    "question1": "“Ula?” ",
    "question2": "“Hmm?” ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "“Don’t kill me for this... but what do you think of going through Sagandzuri with me?” ",
      "response": 101
    }]
  },

{ //this is 93
    "question": " ",
    "question1": " ",
    "question2": " ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": " ",
      "response": 0
    }]
  },

{ //this is 94
    "question": " ",
    "question1": " ",
    "question2": " ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": " ",
      "response": 0
    }]
  },

{ //this is 95
    "question": " ",
    "question1": " ",
    "question2": " ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": " ",
      "response": 0
    }]
  },

{ //this is 96
    "question": " ",
    "question1": " ",
    "question2": " ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": " ",
      "response": 0
    }]
  },

{ //this is 97
    "question": " ",
    "question1": " ",
    "question2": " ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": " ",
      "response": 0
    }]
  },

{ //this is 98
    "question": " ",
    "question1": " ",
    "question2": " ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": " ",
      "response": 0
    }]
  },

{ //this is 99
    "question": " ",
    "question1": " ",
    "question2": " ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": " ",
      "response": 0
    }]
  },

{ //this is 100
    "question": "More routes coming soon!",
    "question1": "You can play Act One of Adam's route or Act One of Ula's route.",
    "question2": " ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "Click here to start over.",
      "response": 0
    }]
  },

{ //this is 101
    "question": "This is the end of Act One. Please click on the first seashell below to go to Act Two.",
    "question1": " ",
    "question2": " ",
    "answers": [{
      "title": "Or you can click here to start over!",
      "response": 0
    }]
  },
];

var currentLocation = 0;

window.printCurrentLocation = function() {
  document.getElementById("question").innerHTML = db[currentLocation].question;
  document.getElementById("question1").innerHTML = db[currentLocation].question1;
  document.getElementById("question2").innerHTML = db[currentLocation].question2;
  document.getElementById("question2").innerHTML = db[currentLocation].question3;
  document.getElementById("question2").innerHTML = db[currentLocation].question4;
  document.getElementById("question2").innerHTML = db[currentLocation].question5;

  var answers = "";
  for (var i = 0, l = db[currentLocation].answers.length; i < l; i++) {
    answers += "<p><button onclick='setLocation(" + db[currentLocation].answers[i].response + ")'>" + db[currentLocation].answers[i].title + "</button></p>";
  }
  document.getElementById("answers").innerHTML = answers;
}

window.setLocation = function(num) {
  currentLocation = num;
  window.printCurrentLocation();
}

window.printCurrentLocation();